# Nicole Ortiz

↓ +1 787-616-5080 

micoleortiz.ga@gmail.com
min/nicoleortizga

github.com/nicoleortizga

## **PROFILE**

Software Developer with experience building and maintaining responsive websites and web applications. Passionate about web development and new technologies, strong technical, business, and interpersonal skills for working in a team and successfully completing small and large scale projects.

### SKILLS

### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS/Sass, SQL

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

¡Query, Vue, 11ty

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, Netlify, Firebase

### PROJECTS & AWARDS

#### **Most Valuable Professional**

Teamwork award for completing online loan and credit card web application project.

#### **Insurance Landing Page**

Responsive landing page built with HTML, CSS/Sass and JavaScript.

#### **Style Stage - Plants on Pink**

Contributed Plants on Pink alternate stylesheet to the community project Style Stage.

# **Home Espresso Machine Care &** Cleaning

Static website to quickly access the Breville Barista Pro care & cleaning step-by-step instructions.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Programmer/Analyst @ Northside ISD

AUGUST 2018 - PRESENT

- Design and develop gueries and stored procedures necessary to support SSRS reports for campus and district staff members.
- Create and maintain SQL scripts to make data corrections and ensure the accuracy of the records.

# Software Developer @ Evertec, Inc.

JUNE 2014 - AUGUST 2018

- Participated in the maintenance, front-end, and back-end development of web payment solutions for financial institutions using the Spring Framework, Ajax, JavaScript, and Web Services.
- Mentor to the recurrent internship program.
- Provided on-call support for deployments to production.

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

# **ATH Móvil Business - Nonprofit Module**

Served as the subject matter expert and internship mentor to work on the admin user interface to manage, activate, and allow nonprofit organizations receive donations.

# EDUCATION

#### Bloc

JUNE 2018 - JUNE 2019 Online Web Development Program

### University of Puerto Rico at Bayamón

AUGUST 2009 - MAY 2014

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science